Finding aid to the Eleanor Terry Lincoln papers CA.MS.01134
Smith College Archives
Eleanor Terry Lincoln papers
1926-1991
Smith College Archives
Lincoln, Eleanor Terry
CA.MS.01134
0.667 linear feet (2 containers)
Eleanor Terry Lincoln was a Professor of English at Smith College from 1934 to 1968. Her papers contain correspondence, course material, news clippings, photographs, publications, and notes documenting her work at Smith.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Until we move into New Neilson in early 2021, collections are stored in multiple locations and may take up to 48 hours to retrieve. Researchers are strongly encouraged to contact Special Collections (specialcollections@smith.edu) at least a week in advance of any planned visits so that boxes may be retrieved for them in a timely manner.
Biographical / Historical
Eleanor Terry Lincoln was born in 1903 in Fergus Falls, Minnesota. She graduated from the University of Minnesota in 1925, and after a two year break to teach high school in Austin, MN, she went on to receive her M.A. at Radcliffe in 1929 and her Ph.D. from Yale in 1938. In 1934, Lincoln came to Smith College as a Professor of English, where she taught until her retirement in 1968. At Smith, Lincoln continued to foster her interest in 17th century literature, writing several books on the Pastoral movement. Outside the classroom, Lincoln filled several administrative positions, including class dean to 1943, 1944, and 1959, chair of the English Department (1960-1963), and as Chair for the Committee on Social Responsibility upon her retirement. After retirement, Lincoln wrote several books on Smith history, including Through the Grecourt Gates, as well as being active in Historic Northampton. She died suddenly in 1994.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains correspondence with other scholars and publishers, course material, news clippings and pamphlets about major events, photographs, publications, and notes from Eleanor Terry Lincoln's time as a Smith Faculty member.
Lincoln, Eleanor Terry
- Prof English 1934-1968, 1956-1991 (Box 927, Folder 1)
- Prof English 1934-1968, 1930-1984 (Box 927, Folder 2)
- Photographs, 1966, undated (Box 927, Folder 3)
- Correspondence – Allesbrook, Mary (Hawes), 1965-1966 (Box 927, Folder 4)
- Correspondence – Davis, Gladys (Wookey), 1964 (Box 927, Folder 5)
- Correspondence – Drew, Elizabeth, 1952-1961 (Box 927, Folder 6)
- Correspondence – Chase, Mary Ellen, 1928-1960 (Box 927, Folder 7)
- Correspondence – Phyllis, Lehmann, 1966-1974 (Box 927, Folder 8)
- Course – M.A. Nicolson SC and Information, 1933-1944 (Box 927, Folder 9)
- Course, 1954 (Box 927, Folder 10)
- Course, 1954 (Box 927, Folder 11)
- General Honors Examination, 1943 (Box 927, Folder 12)
- References, list of illustrators and autographs, undated (Box 927, Folder 13)
- References, Audubon Society, Exhibits at Smith, race/minorities, undated (Box 927, Folder 14)
- References, Literary People, 1983, undated (Box 927, Folder 15)
- Pamphlets, 1968-1975 (Box 927, Folder 16)
- Publications, undated (Box 928, Folder 1)
- Publications – This is the House We Live In, 1982-1983 (Box 928, Folder 2)
- Through the Grecourt Gates typescript, 1978 (Box 928, Folder 3)
- Through the Grecourt Gates, 1978 (Box 928, Folder 4)
- Inauguration 1910 Typescript and notes, undated (Box 928, Folder 5)
- Honorary Degrees, undated (Box 928, Folder 6)
- Pamphlet Poets, 1926-1927 (Box 928, Folder 7)